# **Adam Caplan**

Boston, MA \* (617) 855-5188 \* apcaplan@gmail.com Portfolio: apcaplan.github.io

Software engineer and international yoga teacher with a passion for learning and for helping others to be their best. Over 15 years experience coaching, teaching, problem solving with diverse populations, and creating customized solutions to meet individual needs.

### RECENT PROJECTS

### **Meditation Timer**

- Designed and developed full-stack application with timer and meditation log
- Built using React.js, HTML5, CSS3, Material-UI, Ruby on Rails

### **Sun Salutations**

- Designed and developed full-stack authenticated application with full CRUD actions, offering a fun way to learn, practice, and track yoga sun salutations!
- Built front end client with React.js, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Material-UI, and backend RESTful API with Ruby on Rails

#### **RESTaurant**

- Collaborated with three teammates to create a user-friendly app for restaurants to track inventory
- Built using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, AJAX, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB
- Developed using SCRUM, other Agile methodologies, team version control
- Completed MVP and project requirements in 3 business days

### **Mindfulness Meditation Journal**

- Designed and developed a full-stack, user-friendly app for journaling meditation experiences, tracking changes, observing progress over time
- Built using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3/SASS, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL
- Cloud-based deployment hosting using GitHub pages and Heroku

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Software Engineering Fellow, General Assembly

Boston, Massachusetts

May 2019 - July 2019

- Completed 12 week, 500+ hour immersive course to hone skills in full-stack responsive web application development
- Designed and built four single-page web applications with full CRUD actions, implementing mobile-first, responsive design

### Advanced Yoga and Meditation Teacher, Adam Caplan Yoga

Multiple locations in Thailand, India, and USA

October 2005 - present

- Offer workshops, retreats, trainings, and classes in diverse international communities, to over 500 students per year, with classes ranging in size from private one-on-one's to groups of over 100 students
- Meet with clients to assess goals and needs; develop and deliver custom, individually tailored solutions
- Manage teams of 20-25: lead, supervise, schedule, delegate, counsel, teach, train, mentor, and support yoga teachers

### **Academic and Test Preparation Coach**, PrepMatters

Bethesda, Maryland

August 2003 - August 2007

- Booked over 3,000 hours tutoring students, ages 9-18, in academic subjects and for standardized tests
- Interfaced with clients to assess abilities and goals; designed and implemented custom, individualized plans to meet their needs
- Developed and implemented curricula for pro-bono student groups

## TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

JavaScript HTML React.is CSS Bootstrap jQuery SASS Material-UI Handlebars Rails Node.is Ruby Express.js SQL Mongoose MongoDB Git /GitHub Heroku

### **EDUCATION**

### **Boston University**

Boston, MA
Bachelor of Arts,
English and Religion
Magna Cum Laude,
University Professors
Honors Program

### **City Year Boston**

Corps Member

## YOGA TEACHER CERTIFICATIONS

### **Agama Yoga School**

Koh Phangan, Thailand Yoga Philosophy and Practice, 2,500+ hours formal study

### Hridaya Yoga

Koh Phangan, Thailand (500 hours)

### Agama Yoga School

Koh Phangan, Thailand (500 hours)

### Kripalu Center

Stockbridge, MA (200 hours)